Narrator: Question 1
Speaker: OK, so you need to calculate two thirds of 18%.
First, you need to find one third – so, divide 18 by 3, which equals 6, and then,
to find two thirds, you multiply 6 by 2, which equals 12.
So, the answer is 12%.
Narrator: Question 2
Speaker: To answer this question,
you need to know the formula for calculating the area of a circle,
which is ‘pi multiplied by r squared’.
The value of pi is 3.14 ‘r’ equals the radius of a circle and you can find the radius easily
because it’s half the diameter of the flowerbed, which is 3.9 metres.
So, the radius is 1.95. Squared means multiplied by itself.
So – you may need a calculator for this – 1.95 squared is 3.8, to the nearest decimal point.
Multiply this by pi – 3.14 – and you get 11.9 to the nearest decimal point.
So, the answer is 11.9 square metres.
Narrator: Question 3
Speaker: Most countries use metric measurements, for example,
metres, centimetres, grams, kilos, etc.
Apart from the UK, only the USA, Liberia, and Myanmar use imperial measurements.
In the UK, both are used, but imperial measurements are often preferred,
for example, distances are given in miles, beer is sold in pints or half pints,
and petrol is sold in both litres and gallons.
So, the answer here is 3.5 inches.
An inch is an imperial unit of length and is roughly equivalent to two and a half centimetres.
Narrator: Question 4
Speaker: To calculate the volume of a box,
you simply multiply the width by the height by the length, so 3 multiplied by 5,
which equals 15, multiplied by 8 which equals 120.
So, the answer is 120 cubic centimetres.
Narrator: Question 5
Speaker: Here we know, by adding 2, that April 16th is a Thursday.
By adding 7 each time, we can see that April 23rd and April 30th are also Thursdays,
so the last Thursday is April 30th, also the last day of the month.
This means that none of the options given for the answers is right.
Narrator: Question 6
Speaker: So, according to the question, for every 5 parts of flour we need 2 parts of sugar.
So, first we need to calculate how much 1 part is.
If 5 parts equals a total of 200 grams, then 1 part equals 200 divided by 5, which makes 40.
Then, to calculate 2 parts, we just multiply 40 by 2, so the answer is 80 grams.
Narrator: Question 7
Speaker: Each pie chart shows the sales at one of the cinemas.
If we look at the sections of the pie chart showing Child tickets, that is, the green sections,
we can see that for the Galaxy Cinema, the green section is larger than for the Palace Cinema.
So, the manager’s claim is ‘definitely true’.
Narrator: Question 8
Speaker: First, we need to calculate the total number of accidents in the week,
which is 5 on Monday, 15 on Tuesday, 19 on Wednesday,
5 on Thursday, 16 on Friday, 3 on Saturday, and 7 on Sunday.
Add all of those together – 5 plus 15 is 20, plus 19 makes 39, plus 5 makes 44,
plus 16 makes 60, plus 3 makes 63, plus 7 equals 70.
So, the total number of accidents is 70.
Now we have to calculate the number of serious or major accidents,
which are shown by the blue sections on the bar chart.
So, starting from Monday, we have 2, 3, 5, 2, 6, none on Saturday, and finally 3.
If we add those together, we get 21. So, we need to know what 21 is as a percentage of 70.
The easiest way to do that is to divide 21 by 70, which is 0.3, and then multiply by 100,
which makes 30%.
Or, if you’re using a calculator,
21 divided by 70 and press the percentage button, and the answer is 30%.